Guide to the Ellen Van Volkenburg and Maurice Browne papers vvb
University of Michigan Library (Special Collections Research Center)
- Photographs
  - Photographs of family and friends
    - Photographs of Friends (X), 5 folders
      - Photograph of Ellen Van Volkenburg and Hazel Pearce in Fort Wayne, Indiana, ca. 1893 (Box 36)
      - Group photographs of young women in Ann Arbor, Michigan, 1900-1904; 4 items (Box 36)
      - Photograph of Sara Bard Field and Charles Erskine Scott Wood (Box 36)
      - Photographs of Margaret Brady and Ralph Roeder, ca. 1929-1937; 2 items (Box 36)
      - Unidentified photographs, 12 items (Box 36)
      - Photographs of Ellen Van Volkenburg in the Cornish School office, Arthur Davison Ficke, Mary Aldis, and others, ca. 1919-1969; 73 items (Box 36)
    - Photographs of Molly Underwood and Carol Hollis (XI)
      - Photographs of Molly Underwood, ca. 1942-1945; 3 items (Box 36)
      - Photograph of Carol Hollis, 1937 (Box 36)
    - Photograph album: Pacific Northwest (XIV), ca. 1918 (Box 36)
      Includes images of the Hood Canal, Puget Sound, and other locales.
    - Photograph album: Italy and Dalmatia (XV), ca. 1930 (Box 36)
    - Photograph album: Tunisia and Djerba (XVI), ca. 1931 (Box 36)
    - Photograph album: En route to India, India, and Kashmir (XVII), 1933 (Box 36)
    - Photographs of Italy (XVIII), ca. 1900-1904; 107 items (Box 36)
      104 photographs and 3 glass plate negatives.
    - Photographs of Clovelly, Ranworth, and Wannock, England (XIX), 1906-1907; 62 items (Box 36)
    - Photographs of England (XX), ca. 1913; 6 items (Box 36)
    - Photographs of Wales (XXI), 1912-1913; 17 items (Box 36)
    - Photographs of Porland, Oregon (XXII), 1923; 62 items (Box 36)
    - Photographs of Southern California (XXIII), ca. 1923; 44 items (Box 36)
      Photographs taken during a camping trip and during a trip to Leland-Stanford Juinor University in Stanford, California.
    - Photographs of India (XXIV), 1904-1906; 9 folders; 1072 items (Box 37)
      The photographs are housed in 30 envelopes with notes providing more detail of specific locales.
    - Photographs of India (XXV), 1933; 222 items (Box 37)
      The photographs are housed in 12 envelopes with notes containing more details about specific locales.
    - Photographs of Gripping Lone (XXVI), ca. 1936; 29 items (Box 37)
      "Photographs of 'Gripping Lane', Suffolk, bought by M. B. in or about 1935 and sold by by him in 1943 to Joseph McNeil, Esq., during whose ownership the photos were taken."
    - The Hurdlers dance troup (Box 37)
    - Photographs of Ellen Van Volkenburg (I)
      - Photographs of Ellen Van Volkenburg, 15 items (Drawer 1)
      - Photographs of Ellen Van Volkenburg, 2 items (Drawer 1)
      - Photographs of Maurice Browne in Great Britain, ca. 1928-1932 (Drawer 1)
      - Photograph of Maurice Browne (Drawer 1)
      - Portraits of Maurice Browne, 2 items (Drawer 1)
        Two portraits mounted in a single mat.
      - Portrait of Maurice Browne (Drawer 1)
    - Browne family photographs (V)
      - Photograph of Miss Frankie Browne, ca. 1932 (Drawer 1)
        Photograph by Lavis.
      - Photographs of Ted S. Browne, 1899-1918; 5 items (Drawer 1)
      - Photograph of Major George Browne (Drawer 1)
        Verso: "Presumably this is Major Browne."
      - Photographs of Mrs. George Browne, 2 items (Drawer 1)
        Verso: "Perhaps this is Major Browne's second wife."
      - Photographs of Marsie Browne and family members, ca. 1929; 4 items (Drawer 1)
      - Portrait of Mary Aldis (Drawer 1)
      - Signed portrait of Rupert Brooke, 1914 (Drawer 1)
      - Signed portrait of Arthur Davison Ficke, 1916 (Drawer 1)
      - Signed portrait of Alexander Greene, 1918 (Drawer 1)
      - Signed portrait of John Cowper Powys, 1925 (Drawer 1)
      - Photographs of Eileen Allen, Eugen Jan Boissevain, Arthur Davison Ficke, Edna St. Vincent Millay, Alta Strickley, Dubois Schanck Morris, and Alice Ray (Buell) Morris, 15 items (Drawer 1)
        14 photographs and 1 negative.
    - Photographs of friends (X)
      - Photographs of Mary (Reynolds) Aldis, Charles Erskine Scott Wood, Sara Bard Field, Elena Miramova, Frederic Rolbein, Louis Soelberg, Lionel Solberg, Belle Watson Melville, and Nellie Centenniel Cornish, 7 items (Drawer 1)
      - Photograph of Alpha Theta, 1904 (Drawer 1)
        Includes Ellen Van Volkenburg.
    - Photographs of Maurice Browne, Margaret-Ellen (Janson) Browne, and Maurice Ivar Browne (XI), ca. 1924-1941; 40 items (Drawer 1)
      39 photographs and 1 negative.
    - Photographs of Maurice Browne and Marjorie Morris (XIII), 18 items (Drawer 1)
    - Photographs of Tibetan arts and crafts (XXIV) (Drawer 1)
      5 photographs mounted on a board.
  - Photographs of London and New York (I)
    - Photographs of The Brass Paperweight cast, 1928; 3 items (Drawer 4)
      2 photographs of Maurice Browne and other cast members and 1 caricature.
    - Photographs of The Dark Saint cast, 1928; 7 items (Drawer 4)
    - The Improper Duchess photographs, 1931; 16 items (Drawer 4)
      A London production.
    - Journey's End photographs
      - Photograph of Journey's End cast (Drawer 4)
        Signed photograph of the cast of the Florence Glossup-Harris Co. production of Journey's End, staged at the Colonial Opera House in Hamilton, Bermuda.
      - Photograph of James Whale, 1921 (Drawer 4)
        James Whale directed, produced, and designed the set of Journey's End. Photograph by Hugo N. van Wadenoyen and Son, Cardiff.
      - Photograph of Alister MacDonald, 1930 (Drawer 4)
        Photograph taken during MacDonald's visit to Hollywood to see Journey's End with James Whale and others. Photograph by the Tiffany-Stahl Studio.
      - Photograph of Journey's End audience, November 10, 1929 (Drawer 4)
        Photograph taken at a special performance of Journey's End for recipients of the Victoria Cross, staged at the Prince of Wales Theatre.
      - Photograph of King George V, Queen Mary, and the Duke and Duchess of York at a performance of Journey's End, November 14, 1929 (Drawer 4)
        Photograph of Great Britain's royalty family in the Prince of Wales Theatre's Royal Box.
      - Photographs of Journey's End revival cast, 9 items (Drawer 4)
        Photograph taken in London.
      - "A few photos of individuals"
        - Photograph of "The English Players" of Paris in Munich (Drawer 4)
        - Photograph of Geoffrey Clarke, John Curtis, and Frank Prebble (Drawer 4)
          Photograph by Pollard Crowther.
        - Photograph of Edward Sterling (Drawer 4)
          Photograph of Edward Sterling as Stanhope in the English Players' Paris production of Journey's End. Phtograph by Paul Berger.
        - Photograph of Hugh Williams (Drawer 4)
          Hugh Williams portrayed Stanhope in the Canadian Company production of Journey's End. Photograph by Claude Harris.
      - Photographs of Journey's End cast in Nairobi, Kenya, 1930; 3 items (Drawer 4)
      - Photographs of Journey's End special performance, London, 1929; 3 items (Drawer 4)
      - "Photos of sundry J. E. personalities", London
        - Photograph of Walter Lindsay (Drawer 4)
          Journey's End stage manager. Photograph by Pollard Crowther.
        - Photograph of Thomas Warner (Drawer 4)
          Stage director of Journey's End. Photograph by Pollard Crowther.
        - Photograph of Clifford Hamilton (Drawer 4)
          General manager of Journey's End.
        - Photograph of Maurice Evans (Drawer 4)
          Photograph by E. Cyril Stanborough.
      - Photographs of original Journey's End production, 1929; 56 items (Drawer 4)
        55 photographs and 1 photographic reproduction. The original Journey's End production ran at the Savoy Theatre beginning on January 21, 1929, and moved to the Prince of Wales Theatre in April 1929.
      - Photograph of a memorial plaque (Drawer 4)
      - Photographs of film scenes, 7 items (Drawer 4)
      - Journey's End production stills, 1911 and undated (Box 37)
        Related to Maurice Browne and Juliet Van Volkenburg.
    - Othello photographs
      - Photographs of Othello cast, London, ca. 1930; 33 items (Drawer 3)
      - Photographs of Victoria Cross recipients' signatures, London, 1929; 10 items (Drawer 3)
    - The Unknown Warrior photographs, 1928, 1930; 21 items (Drawer 4)
      1 portfolio and 1 envelope enclosed in portfolio.
    - Photographs of The Venetian cast, 1931; 3 items (Drawer 4)
    - Photographs of White Secrets cast, 1938; 3 items (Drawer 4)
    - Production stills, ca. 1910-1920s (Box 37)
  - Photographs of London and New York (II)
    - Photographic still from All Quiet on the Western Front (Drawer 5)
      Signed by Howard Zoster.
    - Photograph of "And So to Bed", London (Drawer 5)
    - The Betrayal photographs, 1931; 4 items (Drawer 5)
      Little Theatre, London.
    - Candida photographs, 3 items (Drawer 5)
      Greenwich Village Theatre, New York. Photograph by Francis Bruguiere.
    - Photographs of Caviare, a Revue cast, 16 items (Drawer 5)
    - Photograph of John Gielgud in Hamlet (Drawer 5)
      Possibly from Maurice Browne's production of Hamlet at the Queen's Theatre.
    - Photograph of Iphigenia in Aulis rehearsal (Drawer 5)
      Manhattan Opera House.
    - Medea photographs, New York, 1920; 26 items (Drawer 5)
    - Photographs of Muted Strings sets, 4 items (Drawer 5)
    - The Possessed production photographs, October-November 1939; 34 items (Drawer 5)
      Photographs from the Chekhov Theatre production at the Lyceum Theatre, New York. Photographs by Nordhausen.
    - Punchinello photographs
      - Photographs of Punchinello stage designs, 7 items (Drawer 5)
        Stage designs by Laurence Irving.
      - Photographs of Punchinello "first edition", 8 items (Drawer 5)
        Photographs of Robert Farquaharson as Punchinello. Globe Theatre, London.
      - Photographs of Punchinello "second edition", 8 items (Drawer 5)
        Photographs of George Hayes as Punchinello. Globe Theatre, London.
    - School for Slavery photographs, 4 items (Drawer 5)
      Westminster Theatre, London.
    - Photograph of The Trial of Joan of Arc set design, 1921 (Drawer 5)
      Scene design by Ernest de Weerth. Century Theatre, New York.
    - Photographs of Viceroy Sarah cast, 1935; 3 items (Drawer 5)
      Whitehall Theatre, London.
    - Wings over Europe photographs
      - Photographs of Wings over Europe cast, 1928; 4 items (Drawer 5)
      - Photographs of Maurice Browne, Ellen Van Volkenburg, and others, ca. 1930-1932; 23 items (Drawer 5)
        London. 1 portfolio. 1 envelope and loose items enclosed.
    - Women of Ghent photographs, ca. 1934; 2 items (Drawer 5)
      Barn Theatre, Dartington Hall, England.
    - Photographs of Ellen Van Volkenburg, 1939; 9 items (Drawer 5)
      New York. Photographs by Mary Haynsworth.
  - Chicago Little Theatre, Cornish School, and Carmel photographs
    - Photographs of Cornish School production of Aglavaine and Selysette, Seattle, 1919; 5 items (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of Chicago Little Theatre puppet production of Alice's Adventures in Wonderland, Chicago, undated; 22 items (Drawer 6)
    - Photograph of Pasadena Playhouse production of Arsenic and Old Lace, 1943; 6 items (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of Cornish School production of The Bacchae, Seattle, 1931; 9 items (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of Chicago Little Theatre production of Columbine, Chicago, undated; 11 items (Drawer 6)
      10 photographs and 1 photographic reproduction.
    - Photographs of Chicago Little Theatre production of The Constant Lover, Chicago, undated; 4 items (Drawer 6)
      Photographs by Eugene Hutchinson.
    - Photographs of Cornish School students in The Constant Nymph, Seattle, 3 items (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of Chicago Little Theatre production of Creditors, Chicago, 1913; 5 items (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of Cornish School production of Cricket on the Hearth, Seattle, 8 items (Drawer 6)
      Ellen Van Volkenburg's note: "Blanco Posner and ??/and Cricket on the Hearth / Done by Cornish Students / under Alexander Koíransky's direction".
    - Photographs of Chicago Little Theatre puppet production of Deluded Dragon, Chicago, undated; 12 items (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of Cornish School production of Devil's Sabbath, Seattle, 1927; 15 items (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of Repertory Company production of A Doll's House, Seattle, 1921; 27 items (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of Cornish School production of Electra, Seattle, 5 items (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of Chicago Little Theatre production of Grotesque, Chicago, undated; 6 items (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of Chicago Little Theatre production of The Happy Prince, Chicago, undated; 2 items (Drawer 6)
      Photographs by Florence Hendershot.
    - Photographs of Chicago Little Theatre production of Hedda Gabler, Chicago, ca. 1914; 3 items (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of Cornish School production of Iphigenia in Aulis, Seattle, 1934 (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of Chicago Little Theatre production of Jael, Chicago, undated; 4 items (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of Chicago Little Theatre production of Joint Owners in Spain, Chicago, undated; 6 items (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of Seattle production of King Lear's Wife, 7 items (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of C. R. Johnson's stage design for King of the Jews, Chicago, 1916; 2 items (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of Ellen Van Volkenburg in Lithuania, Seattle?, 3 items (Drawer 6)
      Photographs by Rupert Brooke.
    - Photographs of puppets used in Chicago production of The Little Mermaid, 1915? (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of Chicago Little Theatre production of The Lost Silk Hat, Chicago, 3 items (Drawer 6)
      Pohtographs by Eugene Hutchinson.
    - Photographs of Cornish Players production of March of the Bonus Army, Seattle, 10 items (Drawer 6)
      Production directed by Ellen Van Volkenburg.
    - Photographs of Chicago Little Theatre production of Mary Broome, Chicago, ca. 1915; 3 items (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of Chicago Little Theatre production of The Master Builder, Chicago, undated (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of productions of Medea, 1920 and undated; 26 items (Drawer 6)
      Photographs of Chicago Little Theatre production, Chicago (1920), and Theatre Guild production at the Garrich Theatre, New York (undated). 24 photogoraphs, 2 photographic reproductions, and 2 negatives.
    - Photographs of San Francisco puppet production of A Midsummer Night's Dream, ca. 1924; 14 items (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of Repertory Company production of Mr. Faust, Seattle, 1921; 8 items (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of Golden Bough Theatre production of Mother of Gregory, Carmel, ca. 1924-1925; 25 items (Drawer 6)
      Note by Maurice Browne: "The Mother of Gregory / with Ellen van Volkenburg in the title rôle / by Maurice Browne / Margaret Barr as Annie, George Ball as --- Gregory, Edward Kaster as Michael".
    - Photographs of Chicago Little Theatre production of On Baile's Strand, Chicago, undated; 11 items (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of Repertory Company production of The Philanderer, Chicago, undated; 12 items (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of Theatre of the Golden Bough production of The Princess Who Wouldn't Say Die, Carmel, ca. 1924; 5 items (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of Cornish School production of The Shewing-up of Blanco Posnet, Seattle, 1921; 15 items (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of Repertory Company production of Tidings Brought to Mary, Seattle, 1921; 15 items (Drawer 6)
    - The Trojan Women photographs
      - Photographs of The Trojan Women transcontinental tour, 1915; 33 items (Drawer 6)
        31 photographs and 2 negatives.
      - Photographs of Cornish School production of The Trojan Women, Seattle, 1926; 14 items (Drawer 6)
      - Photographs of Mildred Gellendré Theatre Studio production of The Trojan Women, New York, 1955; 19 items (Drawer 6)
        18 photographs and 1 note listing cast members. Production directed by Ellen Van Volkenburg Browne.
      - Photographs of Chicago Little Theatre production of The Trojan Women, Chicago, 1913?; 55 items (Drawer 7)
    - Photographs of Chicago Little Theatre production of Womenkind, Chicago, undated; 4 items (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of Repertory Company production of Yesterday's Husband, Seattle, 1921; 10 items (Drawer 6)
    - Carmel Summer School photographs, 1924; 17 items (Drawer 6)
      Photographs by Josselyn, Lewis.
    - Chicago Little Theatre photograph, ca. 1912-1918 (Drawer 6)
      Postcard photograph.
    - Photographs of Chicago Little Theatre passion play, 1916; 6 items (Drawer 6)
      Possible title: A Christmas Pantomime. Photographs by Eugene Hutchinson.
    - Photograph of Chicago Little Theatre tea room (Drawer 6)
      Photograph by Kaufmann, Weimer and Fabry Co.
    - Photographs of unidentified Cornish School productions, Seattle, 22 items (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of puppets and puppeteers, 12 items (Drawer 6)
    - Photographs of Tacoma Drama League productions, 4 items (Drawer 6)
      Photographs by Chapin Bowen.
    - Composite photograph of an unidentified play (Drawer 6)
      Composite comprised of 6 individual images.
    - Maurice Browne note, 1946 (Drawer 6)
      Regarding photographs of Chicago Little Theatre productions.
    - Glass negatives and prints regarding The Trojan Women, Joint Owners in Spain, Alice in Wonderland puppet play, and additional unidentified productions (Box 38)
      Unidentified productions may be Chicago Little Theatre productions.
  - Photographs of Associates
    - "Photographs of Chicago Little Theatre Players and Guest-Artists, Pacific Coast Players, and Portraits of Chicago Little Theatre Notabilities" (Drawer 7)
      Includes Louis Alter, Esther Blumenstock, Beulah Bondi (a.k.a. Beulah Bondy), Bernadine Carver, Loretta Clark, Winifred Cutting, Helen Head Fivey, Facelia Hamlin, Marguerite Hertz, Arthur Johnson, Miriam Kiper, Rolla Lyon, John Stokes McCune, Truly Jean McWilliams, Lou Wall Moore, Edard Moseman, Elma Pease, Daniel Reed, Betty Ross, Eugene Stockdale, Winifred Taylor, and Kathleen Wheeler.
    - Photographs of Rupert Brooke, 3 items (Drawer 7)
      Photograps by Eugene Hutchinson. 1 negative and 2 prints.
    - Photographs of Robert Frost, Wilfrid Wilson Gibson, Miriam Marmein, Marie Mayer, and Ralph Roeder, 1910 and undated (Drawer 7)
    - Photographs of Chekhov Theatre Studio, Ridgefield, Connecticut, ca. 1939-1942; 8 items (Drawer 7)
    - Photographs of Michael Chekhov, September 26-27, 1942 (Drawer 7)
      Photograph of Michael Chekhov in Anton Chekhov's I Forgot, Barbizon Plaza Theatre.
    - Photographs of Beatrice Straight, ca. 1939-1942; 3 items (Drawer 7)
      Beatrice Straight in various roles for the Chekhov Theatre Studio in Ridgefield, Connecticut.
    - Photographs of Robert Malise Bowyer Nichols, 2 items (Drawer 7)
    - Photograph of Richard Odlin, ca. 1957 (Drawer 7)
    - Photograph of Phidelah Rice (Drawer 7)
      Photograph by Alice Austin.
    - Photographs of Peter Ridgeway, 2 items (Drawer 7)
    - Photograph of Ellen Terry (Drawer 7)
      Photograph by Lena Connell, London.
    - Photographs of Richard Teschner, 6 items (Drawer 7)
      2 photographs and 4 picture postcards. Photographs by Clarion, Vienna.
    - Photographs of Ellen Van Volkenburg and Rupert Brooke on board the S.S. Philadelphia, 1914; 15 items (Drawer 7)
    - Photographs of Dorothy Fuller, Rosalinde Fuller, and Cynthia Fuller, 14 items (Drawer 7)
    - Photograph of Chicago Little Theatre personnel, ca. 1912 (Drawer 7)
      Photograph by Matzene, Chicago.
    - Photographs of Brabazon-Lowther, Witter Bynner, Iris De Luce, Nicholas Vachel Lindsay, Leon M. Lion, Arthur Knowles Sabin, and Robert Vivian, 1914-1916 and undated (Drawer 7)
    - Photograph of Nellie C. Cornish (Drawer 7)
      Photograph by Richard Erichson.
    - Photograph of Samuel, Berkeley-Hill, Welland Lathrop, Moroni Olsen, and Claiborne Townsend (Drawer 7)
    - Autographed photographs of Yvonne Arnaud, Sir Ben Greet, and Sir Ronald Storrs, 1929-1952 (Drawer 7)
    - Photograph of a drawn portrait of Edgar Lee Masters, July 20, 1921 (Drawer 7)
      Portrait dated 1916; inscription dated July 20, 1921.
    - Photographs of and newspaper clippings regarding Lawrance D'Orsay, 1931 (Drawer 7)
    - Photographs of an unidentified woman and and an unidentified couple, 2 items (Drawer 7)
      Photographs by Leonid Fink.
    - Photograph of Katina Paxinou, 1939 (Drawer 7)
      Inscribed "Athène".
    - Photograph of James Meighan, John Drinkwater, and Robert Nichols, ca. 1917-1926 (Drawer 7)
      Photograph by Eugene Hutchinson.
    - Photographs of Chicago Little Theatre players, 1914 and undated (Drawer 7)
      Includes Margaret T. Allen, John Coeburn, Mrs. Samuel Edgerton, Elizabeth Goodrich Rickett, Miriam Kiper, Lester Luther, John Stokes McCune, Edward H. Pasmore, Stella Perugini, Juliana Randolph, Helen Robbins, and George F. Wolff.
    - Photographs of Dorothy (Whitney) Elmhirst, Michael Chekhov, and Beatrice Straight, Dartington Hall, Totnes, England, 3 items (Drawer 7)
    - Photographic postcard of Ada (Cooper) Galsworthy (Drawer 7)
    - Photographs of Michael Chekhov, 4 items (Drawer 7)
    - Photographs of Dartington Dance-Drama Group, 25 items (Drawer 7)
    - Photographs of George P. Lester, London, 5 items (Drawer 7)
      Photographs by Hughes.
    - Photographs of Dartington Hall production of Comus, 1928; 14 items (Drawer 7)
    - Photograph of Ludmilla Pitoëff (Drawer 7)
      Photograph of a photograph.
    - Photographs of John Gielgud, 2 items (Drawer 7)
      Photographs by Raphael, London.
    - Photograph of a painted portrait of a woman (Drawer 7)
      Photograph by Reynolds Photo, Paris.
    - Photograph of Alastair Sim's daughter, 1955 (Drawer 7)
    - Photographic postcards of Moskauer Hebräisches Künstler-Theater productions of "Habima", 13 items (Drawer 7)
    - Photograph of Margaret Brady, Tacoma, Washington (Drawer 7)
    - Photograph of a painting of Witter Brynner, ca. 1939 (Drawer 7)
      Inscribed to Maurice Browne.
    - Photograph of Nellie C. Cornish (Drawer 7)
      Photograph by Kennell-Ellis, Seattle.
    - Photograph of a photograph of John Drinkwater (Drawer 7)
      Photograph by Hall Studio, New York.
    - Photograph of Edith Lees Ellis (Mrs. Havelock Ellis) (Drawer 7)
      Photographic reproduction.
    - Postcard photograph of Edith Lees Ellis (Mrs. Havelock Ellis) (Drawer 7)
      Photograph by J. Caswell Smith, London. Signed.
    - Photographs of Le Petit Théâtre du Vieux Carré production of St. Joan, New Orleans, 1929; 11 items (Drawer 7)
      Includes 9 photographs, a newspaper clipping with a review of the play, and a letter from the director to the members of the theatre who participated in the production.
    - Photograph of Mary Wigman (Drawer 7)
      Photograph by Sasha.
    - Photograph of Barbara Ames, ca. 1962 (Drawer 7)
      Photograph by Roy Schatt.
    - "Photographs of some Pacific Coast Players with Ellen Van Volkenburg and Maurice Browne", ca. 1919-1924 (Drawer 7)
      Includes Betty Barr, Margaret Barr, Robert Bell, Byron Foulger, Marjorie Morris, Moroni Olsen, Carlisle Tuppen, Annchen Vån Gaal, and Janet Young.
    - Photograph of Ellen Van Volkenburg and Marian Anderson at Mackinac Island, Michigan, 1946 (Drawer 7)
    - Photographs of Adrienne Ames with Mary Servoss and Beatrice Straight, 2 items (Drawer 7)
      Photographs by Al Hauser, New York.
    - Photograph of Beatrice Straight, ca. 1953 (Drawer 7)
      Photograph by Marcus Blechman.
    - Photograph of Edward Paul dePont (Drawer 7)
      Photograph by Alexander.
    - Photographs of Emma Knox McGaw, ca. 1948-1958; 2 items (Drawer 7)
    - Photograph of Colin Keith-Johnstone (Drawer 7)